Victoria Wood: Hello.
Surabhi Simha: Hi.
Surabhi Simha: Thank you for all your help.
Victoria Wood: Of course, of course.
Victoria Wood: I'm looking forward to this.
Surabhi Simha: Oop.
Victoria Wood: Hello!
Surabhi Simha: Do you have been driving.
Victoria Wood: I can't hear Lena for some reason. Can you?
Surabhi Simha: insane.
Victoria Wood: Sergeant.
Surabhi Simha: I heard the hello, but nothing after.
Surabhi Simha: Lena, can you hear us?
Lena Ting (she/her): Yeah.
Surabhi Simha: Okay.
Lena Ting (she/her): But I… I don't know what… okay, wait, this is horrible.
Victoria Wood: We can hear you now, yeah.
Victoria Wood: Or at least I can.
Lena Ting (she/her): I gotta clean out my office.
Lena Ting (she/her): We have 3 more fellowships to work on.
Lena Ting (she/her): And I still have not turned in my grades.
Surabhi Simha: You muted myself.
Monica Daley (she, her): Were you teaching this summer?
Lena Ting (she/her): Yeah.
Monica Daley (she, her): -Oh.
Lena Ting (she/her): Nope, nope.
Lena Ting (she/her): I only teach a summer class, because…
Lena Ting (she/her): It's a clinical experience class, so it's not…
Monica Daley (she, her): Yo…
Lena Ting (she/her): Not… Not much, but not… nothing.
Victoria Wood: Alright, we can give people another minute or so to join in here, but, while we're waiting…
Victoria Wood: For those of you that are already online, I did want to give a quick reminder. I think most people have already let me know about their capstone Symposium scheduled time for their team. I followed up with a few teams I haven't heard from yet, so please do let me know.
Victoria Wood: As soon as you can, so that, if you… if your team can't make it to your scheduled talk, so that we can move things around if needed. I'd like to send out the final program next week.
Victoria Wood: But that is separate from the individual RSVPs. I do need everybody who plans, especially if you're planning on attending in person, to submit your RSVP by the end of next week, so that we can make sure we have appropriate headcounts and things for, and food restrictions, dietary restrictions for catering and such.
Victoria Wood: And then, if you need me to help you with a roommate search, please make sure to submit the roommate form. So I have a lot of, forms floating around. I'm gonna put them all in the chat now, so that you can, see those.
Victoria Wood: Sorry.
Lena Ting (she/her): Haven't signed up.
Surabhi Simha: slow question.
Surabhi Simha: I don't remember if I signed up. Is there a way to check?
Victoria Wood: I can check for you, yeah, yeah.
Surabhi Simha: Oh.
Victoria Wood: I'll let you know after.
Surabhi Simha: Awesome, thank you.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, for sure.
Lena Ting (she/her): I did not sign up.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, so please do that. If you submit it twice, that's fine too, I can filter out names.
Monica Daley (she, her): I can deduplicate later.
Victoria Wood: I think that's a lot easier than having missing names. So, yeah, if you're not sure if you submitted, happy to check for you, that's easy for me.
Victoria Wood: But you can also just submit twice.
Victoria Wood: Cool! If you have any questions about the Capstone Symposium, let me know. I will, like I said, I'm gonna try to send out that final program in the next week or so. So, cool.
Monica Daley (she, her): Can I ask a question about the code for today before we get started? So I downloaded the installer, but then that loaded very slowly on my Mac, and so I downloaded the source code and ran it from the source code instead. Is that okay? Is that gonna work?
Surabhi Simha: Yes, yeah, so I will actually bring up the slide multiple times to walk people through, because, this is also me testing out how this works, and I did, like, briefly test, and it turns out it is quite slow.
Surabhi Simha: So…
Monica Daley (she, her): And it seems like on a Mac, silicon, it has to run through Rosetta, so it's basically slow because it's not designed to run on a silicon Mac, so there's, like, a translation layer, but…
Monica Daley (she, her): If you download the source code, it seems to run natively in my… through my MATLAB 2025 just fine. So…
Surabhi Simha: Ugh.
Monica Daley (she, her): There was something about the different… the version that was… the installer was based on.
Surabhi Simha: Yeah, so this is my very first time, like, trying out an installer option, and I was thinking this is because MATLAB is an expensive license, and I was trying to make it more broadly available.
Surabhi Simha: So it turns out that MATLAB lets you, do that by… it basically… it's still MATLAB code, but it encrypts it, so then it's okay if you don't have a license.
Surabhi Simha: And then, I think because of that, there's probably a limitation. Maybe that's… I didn't know it ran through as it is, so… so I guess it limits what… how it works, and I.
Monica Daley (she, her): Possibly, but I don't really know all of the details.
Surabhi Simha: Yeah, yeah. But serving… That's good to know.
Lena Ting (she/her): a Mac.
Monica Daley (she, her): Yeah, it runs on my Mac fine if I just use the source code instead of the installer. That's all. And, the other thing, little minor thing was, like, you have to know how to enable your Mac to install it, so you have to override the security settings. That's the other thing with the installer.
Surabhi Simha: Yeah.
Monica Daley (she, her): Yeah.
Surabhi Simha: Thank you. I did learn that when I tried, so I'm gonna mention that during the presentation, too.
Monica Daley (she, her): Sorry, okay, I'm getting ahead of things, and I just…
Surabhi Simha: Yeah, this weekend.
Monica Daley (she, her): Other people are ready to…
Surabhi Simha: Yeah.
Monica Daley (she, her): Run the software. Yes.
Surabhi Simha: And Windows has its own problems, too, so I will mention that too.
Surabhi Simha: I only recently learned after I sent out the code, but, thank you. And I actually do appreciate people telling me this. Like I said, it's my first time, so you're all my beta testers, so please keep the feedback coming.
Surabhi Simha: Thanks.
Victoria Wood: One more quick thing before I hand it over to you to fully start, Surabhi. I realize that for the watch parties, it's a bit hard for some of you to post in the chat or unmute if you have questions, so today, I'm going to post a
Victoria Wood: post in the Slack, the general channel, for you to be able… if you reply to that with any questions you have, I'll monitor that and read it out to Surabi as she presents today, so that way people on watch parties can also ask questions if you have them.
Victoria Wood: That's all I have.
Victoria Wood: So you can go ahead when you're ready.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, can you now hear me and see my main presentation slide? Okay, great.
Surabhi Simha: Awesome. Thanks everyone for joining this tutorial on muscle spindle modeling.
Surabhi Simha: I'm going to explain a little bit about the muscle spindles itself, and walk you through a model we've developed, and are trying to publish some work on.
Surabhi Simha: Oh.
Surabhi Simha: So, here's an outline for what you can expect.
Surabhi Simha: Ideally, by the end of this tutorial, you'll have some brief understanding of the muscle spindle. It won't be detailed, so it'll be just sufficient to, like, know why and how to use the model, but there'll be question time, so you can ask lots more questions then.
Surabhi Simha: And then hopefully you'll have a working model of the muscle spindle on your computers, so we'll spend some time installing and making sure it runs.
Surabhi Simha: And, I'll walk through, how each part of the model works, so that you can… you have some intuition for what each thing's do. And then, if there's time,
Surabhi Simha: you'll also run… you'll try to get to… not run your own data, but there's an example data set that you can use, but I'll at least explain how you can go about running your own data through the model.
Surabhi Simha: This is the outline for the talk itself, so this is just the setup and housekeeping that we're talking about now. Then, like I said, I'll briefly talk about the muscle spindle, and we will model it as a biophysical model, and I'll explain why.
Surabhi Simha: We'll walk through the, muscle spindle model. So, if some of you have already downloaded the,
Surabhi Simha: source code. There, when you launch it, you might have seen two GUIs. We'll mostly go through the learning tutorial today.
Surabhi Simha: Then, we'll break out into rooms, and give you plenty of time to… because it's also slow, I'll give you plenty of time to, like, work through and try different things, and again, try to break it, because it's good feedback for me.
Surabhi Simha: We'll spend some time discussing what you find, and then I'll walk you through the… how you can run your own code.
Surabhi Simha: So that's the rough outline.
Surabhi Simha: Yeah, so, like I was telling Monica, this is, these are instructions that you already had, but if anyone hasn't, done this yet, here's the link again.
Surabhi Simha: I guess?
Surabhi Simha: still have to type it out, sorry. I just realized, copy-paste, but this is the link, so if you go to this link, you can just scroll to the bottom. There's lots of things you can read for information, but also you can just scroll right to the bottom, where you'll see, 3 or 4 files.
Surabhi Simha: Two of the files will just be installers. There'll be one for Mac and one for Windows. This requires you to have no MATLAB. You don't have to have MATLAB installed on your computer. When you open and run the installer, it will download
Surabhi Simha: the specific MATLAB things that you require. It'll download and install, which is also why it might take some time, it might be a big file. So hopefully you've done this before. If not, this is a good time to start it, because I'll spend some time talking about the muscle spindle so it can install during that time.
Surabhi Simha: And, yeah, as also Monica mentioned, like, it's an app, basically, which means your computer… and your computer doesn't know who created the app, so it tries to reject it, so you'll have to give it permissions, and you'll say, I promise there's no virus in it, so you can give it permission, so you might have to,
Surabhi Simha: right-click and run as admin, and it might also ask you questions, depending on whether you're Mac or Windows, but it'll ask you, are you sure you want to run it? So you'll have to, like, walk through that.
Surabhi Simha: I did notice with Windows users, if you do, if you don't run as admin, it opens just your blank page, but if you do run as admin, it will run.
Surabhi Simha: And then if you do have MATLAB, you can, you have multiple options. You can do the same thing as, if you don't have MATLAB, which is you download the installer, download the installer.
Surabhi Simha: Or you can download the source code, which is a zip file at the bottom of that page, and it's just a bunch of scripts. It'll open up as a folder, and it'll have all the various scripts associated with it.
Surabhi Simha: You can also do a third thing, which is just clone the repository that this is associated with. For this tutorial, I would suggest not doing that, simply because that… when you clone the repository.
Surabhi Simha: it, every time I make changes, I push it to the repository, so it might have… I tried to make sure I did not update the repository since giving out this link, but in case I did and forgot, you might get slight changes. So, if you're working in a breakout room with others and they have different, slight changes to the code, it might cause confusion. So, if you just download the source code, it's a rendered code, so it's just one copy that
Surabhi Simha: you all definitely have the same, part. So, I would suggest doing that for this, session.
Surabhi Simha: Yeah, just, any quick questions about the sprite before I go… Enter it.
Surabhi Simha: I actually don't know how to sing.
Surabhi Simha: those questions.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, I'll assume no questions.
Surabhi Simha: Yeah, okay.
Surabhi Simha: Oh yeah, I see here, I can see chats. Okay, those… I don't see chat questions in chat, okay.
Surabhi Simha: Cool. Oh yeah, this is the sign-in sheet. I'll bring this up again a couple of times in case you join late or leave early. I think all trainees, if you can just sign in, use the QR code and sign in, that'll be great.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, so I'm going to some science of what is a muscle spindle, and why we model it the way we do.
Surabhi Simha: The muscle spindle generates sensory signals that is useful for movement.
Surabhi Simha: I have a very quick activity to get us started to understand the muscle spindle. So, those of you watching, if you can stand up. It's not necessary to stand up, but if you can, it'll be great if you do stand up.
Surabhi Simha: I see, I'm assuming. Oh yeah, I see, two people, thank you.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, it's very simple. Hmm.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, look straight ahead.
Surabhi Simha: Hopefully?
Surabhi Simha: I'll tell you the instructions. Now, raise one foot off the ground.
Surabhi Simha: It's not a balanced task, so if you need to hold onto something for balance, please do. Please do not fall.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, one foot off the ground. Now, use the toes of the foot that's raised, and use it to touch the shin of your other leg.
Surabhi Simha: And scratch your shin if you can.
Surabhi Simha: Now you can put the foot back down.
Surabhi Simha: And you can sit down if you just stood up. That was the activity. Thank you for participating.
Surabhi Simha: So, the little muscle spindle lesson here is that the reason you could do it, at least the two people I saw looked at it pretty easily, I think. The reason you could do it is because you used muscle spindles.
Surabhi Simha: use other things too, but, one of the things that helped me do this, oh, was there a question?
Surabhi Simha: Maybe not. Yeah, so the reason you could do it so easily was,
Surabhi Simha: like, you were all looking through your head, so you did not know where your foot was, you did not know where your shin was, at least you did not visually know where it was. But I'm guessing, on your first try, your foot touched your shin. It did not, like…
Surabhi Simha: You weren't kicking foot straight ahead, or you weren't kicking out to the side, or anything like that. And, you were able to, like, find your sh… use your foot to find your shin and scratch it.
Surabhi Simha: So this sense of what your body is doing, comes from, some signals from muscle spindles. Now, it's not that, like, directly a muscle spindle sensory signal that lets you do this. It's the sensory signal that's being processed through, various regions of your nervous system.
Surabhi Simha: But there is also another,
Surabhi Simha: Functional behavior or tasks that you might be, used to, where we can see, like, quite directly the sensory signal from the muscle spindle, contributing to movement.
Surabhi Simha: So here, this is a tendon tap, where you can take a little tiny ham in, you can tap your tendon, the idea being that you stretch your tendon, and when you stretch the tendon, the muscle that's attached to it, we're now dealing with the quadriceps, the muscle gets stretched.
Surabhi Simha: And when the muscle gets stretched, you have the muscle spindle that's within this muscle, we'll talk more about that later, but this muscle spindle within it also gets stretched, and you get this little, muscle spindle sensory signal. And here, I'm showing one of the loops that I mentioned, where the muscle spindle signal,
Surabhi Simha: Like, monosynaptically, that's, like, directly synapses onto this alpha motor neuron, which activates your quartriceps muscle.
Surabhi Simha: So, this is one way your muscle spindle sensory signal can, directly affect your,
Surabhi Simha: movement generation. By that, I mean your motor activity to your muscle. But of course, there are other loops, too, and you can already see one more here, where there is, like, you have a couple of more synapses.
Surabhi Simha: And through that, your muscle spindle signal can affect, your, antagonist muscle, and, it… also, you have other loops with more synapses, which,
Surabhi Simha: Eventually, it lets you do something like, find… know where your foot is, and help you, sketch a shin.
Surabhi Simha: So today, we're going to be mostly focusing at this level, where we look… model the muscle spindle and the sensory signal that comes out of it, and hopefully you'll learn enough that, you know, you can then use this model to put it into all these other loops, and
Surabhi Simha: Understand other behaviors.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, so, the muscle spindle is a small muscle inside a muscle. So, here's, this extrafusal muscle. Now, because we are dealing with multiple muscle fibers, we're gonna call the skeletal muscle, or the big muscle, as the extrafusal muscle. And, inside, like.
Surabhi Simha: embedded within the fibers of this extrafusal muscle, you have the muscle spindle. So now the muscle spindle has this big capsule. Yeah, so this, muscle spindle is mostly… we, mostly assumed that the muscle spindle is in parallel to these extrafusal muscle fibers.
Surabhi Simha: And, it consists of this capsule, that is the whole spindle, and within that, it consists of muscle fibers. And these we'll now call as intrafusal muscle fibers.
Surabhi Simha: Now, there are actually three types of intrafusal muscle fibers, bag 1, bag 2, and chain. This cartoon here shows you two types. So this, Jounder's cushier one is the bag 1 muscle fiber, and then this thin rod-like one is the chain muscle fiber, but,
Surabhi Simha: The BAC2 properties are,
Surabhi Simha: close to chain fibers, basically intermediate, but for the purpose of this model and this cartoon, we're going to lump the back two and chain into one muscle fiber that I might
Surabhi Simha: I think I'll usually call it just the chain, interfusal muscle fiber.
Surabhi Simha: And then, there is the muscle spindle sensory signal. That is the 1A afferent. Now, you can see there are two afferents coming out of the muscle spindle. There's the 1A afferent, and there is the group 2 afferent.
Surabhi Simha: Oh, is that a question?
Surabhi Simha: Yeah, so there is the 1A group 1A primary afferent, so I might use a lot of different names, but primary 1A afferent refers to the signal, which is
Surabhi Simha: It's measured from all the types of intrafusal muscle fibers. So, if you can sort of see, you can see this, it connects to both cartoons here.
Surabhi Simha: Just to show that it's reading from both types of muscle fibers. Your group 2 afferent, on the other hand, it only connects to this thin rod one, chain one.
Surabhi Simha: And it is also very important, it also contributes to your proprioception and sensing of your body, but today we'll mostly focus on the 1A primary afferent.
Surabhi Simha: And then, now here's the fun thing. Like, unlike most of your sensory organs, the muscle spindle has its own motor drive. So remember, there's the extrafusal muscle, which receives alpha motor drive, which is what helps it activate… activates it and contracts and generate movement.
Surabhi Simha: Similarly, each of these interfusal fibers, they receive their own gamma motor drive.
Surabhi Simha: So we have two types, because we're showing two muscle fibers. There's the gamma dynamic, which goes to the bagged muscle fiber, and then the gamma static, which goes to the chain muscle fiber. So these help activate, and they're also known as the fusimotor neurons, so they help activate the interfusal muscle fibers.
Surabhi Simha: So that's the overview of the muscle spindle and how we'll address it, and because that's a cartoon, I just wanted to show a couple of more realistic, images of the muscle spindle. So this is,
Surabhi Simha: image from under a microscope, of, a muscle spindle. So, in this case, I believe this was,
Surabhi Simha: from a cat, where they actually did the hard work of dissecting the muscle… muscle spindle, and then they placed the muscle spindle, like, under a microscope. So,
Surabhi Simha: I'm gonna try and remember… so the C refers to the capsule, so this whole capsule you see here, that's this line, so that's showing you the muscle spindle. And then M, I believe, refers to the intrafusal muscle fibers, so it's the whole bundle, you can't actually see the different muscle
Surabhi Simha: intrafusal fibers, like in the cartoon. But this is the interfusal fibers.
Surabhi Simha: So P is the primary 1A afferent, so this 1A afferent that's coming out in the cartoon here, that's this thick line, and S is the secondary afferent, that's the group 2 afferent that I referred to.
Surabhi Simha: So this is what your muscle spindle looks like under a microscope when the spindle is dissected out.
Surabhi Simha: This is another image, more, much more recent. I think they're separated by, like, three decades or something, or much more, actually. So here, in this case,
Surabhi Simha: what… this is a whole muscle, and they kept the whole muscle, but they permeabilized it. So now, I don't know if you can actually see, but each of these arrows is pointing to a muscle spindle.
Surabhi Simha: So you can see, like, a thin white line, maybe? There's a thin white line here. So those are all muscle spindles. And, the idea here, what I wanted to try to show is that you can see the muscle spindles are roughly in parallel to the muscle, so this whole thing is your muscle.
Surabhi Simha: And these are your, I think these are your nerves, but I think they are your… they go to your alpha… the alpha tribe, not the gamma tribe nerves. And this is a zoomed-in image of the muscle spindle from here, so I think they zoomed into one of these thin lines.
Surabhi Simha: And, so it's trying to highlight this is the equatorial region, or the center. So that's this part, and you can see the afferents, or the 1A afferent especially, measures out of the central portion of the spindle, that's around here.
Surabhi Simha: And then your, gamma drives usually go, to the sides, so the carton's showing you here the, the polar regions, and that, I think these arrows over here. So, your muscle spindle can be fairly long, which,
Surabhi Simha: your afferent reads one portion, and your motor endings go to another.
Surabhi Simha: Yeah, so this is… this is how a spindle would look like under a microscope. Maybe some of you, I know some of you do, like, biology, like, in vivo work, or, like, dissecting and stuff, so maybe this gives you a better idea of what it
Surabhi Simha: Spindle might look like.
Surabhi Simha: Okay. Yeah, so like I said, we'll focus on the 1A afferent. Oh, I forgot to mention the 1B, but the 1B does not measure from the spindle, it's the Golgi tendinoid, which you might have heard, and it's at the interface of the
Surabhi Simha: Extrafusal muscle and your tendon, and it, we think it measures the force from, your extrafusal muscles when the muscles contract.
Surabhi Simha: But today, we'll focus on the primary 1A afferent muscle spindle.
Surabhi Simha: I should also say, if you have questions, please, just ask.
Surabhi Simha: So,
Surabhi Simha: like I said, I'm going to jump… there are lots of properties to the muscle spindle, but I'm going to jump into one property that, guides and motivates how we model our muscle spindle, which is that, the muscle spindle 1A firing, especially, is history-dependent, just like the muscle force output. Now, I know you've, heard about the muscle
Surabhi Simha: muscles, extrafusal muscles, and they're modeling in the last two lectures, and I believe you also heard a little bit… a bit about the history dependence of the muscle force, so I'll be brief. Couple of things when I mean by history dependence here. There are many properties of history dependence. Couple of things that I'm referring to here are the short-range stiffness. So now here in the bottom row, this is from an extrafusal muscle.
Surabhi Simha: And you have your, muscle length changes.
Surabhi Simha: Where the muscle is continuously stretched and shortened. And you can see in the first time the muscle is stretched, when
Surabhi Simha: For going from staying relaxed, there is a steep increase in muscle force, which is, shown as stress in the top row.
Surabhi Simha: Now, this is your short-chain stiffness.
Surabhi Simha: And then you can look at the corresponding, stretch.
Surabhi Simha: It's the same length change, the muscles going through the same length and velocity, but the force now is different. So this is history dependence. There are, of course, other forms of def- the other definitions, which I think you heard last classes, they also apply. These are just a couple of examples.
Surabhi Simha: Now, this is forged from an extrafusal muscle, and here's a parallel of muscle spindle 1A affinity from a muscle spindle.
Surabhi Simha: So, once again, if you keep… hold the muscle spindle at rest, this is a muscle tendon unit length at the bottom.
Surabhi Simha: But, if you recall, I said the muscle spindles, we can assume them to be roughly parallel to the muscle fib… extrafusal muscle. So we can plot this muscle tendon unit length, and we can assume these length changes are what's approximately experienced by the
Surabhi Simha: A muscle spindle. So, when you first hold the muscle spindle at rest, and you stretch it, you get this, initial burst, which is a high, muscle spindle firing.
Surabhi Simha: Now,
Surabhi Simha: This can be seen as a panel of short-chain stiffness, which is also a sharp increase in force from the muscle. And similarly, if you look at the next stretch, so going through the same stretch of the muscle and muscle spindle, you now have a… you don't have the initial burst, and you also have a different slope of firing. So, given this panel in
Surabhi Simha: Like, given these similar properties that are parallel between extrafusal muscle force and muscle spindle firing.
Surabhi Simha: And we know that, which you also heard in the last two lectures, that these histories arise from cross-bridge dynamics, at least for the muscle force.
Surabhi Simha: And there is some literature suggesting that,
Surabhi Simha: This might also be responsible for the history dependence of the muscle spindle.
Surabhi Simha: And we know that the muscle spindles are also made of muscle fibers, just slightly different muscle fibers. So, given all these reasons, we basically model a muscle spindle based on cross-bridge dynamics.
Surabhi Simha: So, here is the model, which this figure, should also pop up in the tutorial, when you use it.
Surabhi Simha: So, our model consists of essentially muscle fibers. So, we have, this little section in the center is the muscle, so we have the extrafusal muscle.
Surabhi Simha: And then there's a tendon attached to it. And in parallel with the extrafusal muscle fiber, we have the intrafusal muscle fibers. So our model essentially consists of three types of muscle fibers. They are all modeled similarly, that is, meaning that we model the cross-bridge dynamics, but they are given different properties,
Surabhi Simha: largely, for the extra fuel muscle, I think you heard how people try to measure the properties. For the spindle, too, they try to measure it, but there's a lot more guesswork for the properties of the muscle spindle fibers, because we don't have mechanical tests the same way we have for extrafusal muscle fibers.
Surabhi Simha: But, they do have different properties that are all fit to the firing rate, and so that's how we generate three different, cross-bridge muscle models.
Surabhi Simha: And, each muscle, model gets its own input of activations, and, like I said, there's alpha motor activations and gamma motor activations, and then the force that comes out
Surabhi Simha: gets added up as a linear sum, force and yank. I'll go… I'll explain all this again in the next slide, where we take the force in yank, that's the rate of change of force from the intrafusal fibers, to convert it into a receptor potential. So, the receptor potential arrives here, and then it gets converted to a firing rate that's basically spikes and action potentials that you would measure from a nerve in your experiments.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, so that's the… Overview. Any questions until now, before I go into the model itself?
Surabhi Simha: Cool.
Surabhi Simha: That background?
Surabhi Simha: Okay, we're gonna talk again about trying to set this up to make sure everyone actually has the model running.
Surabhi Simha: So, in this case, it'll actually help. We still want… you don't need the model yet. You'll, really need it when you're going to breakout rooms.
Surabhi Simha: But all the slides from in this section, I'll use screenshots from the tutorial window, so if you also have it running and can look, well, basically go through the tutorial window, it might just help you follow along with the screenshots that I'm showing.
Surabhi Simha: So, once again.
Surabhi Simha: If you don't… if you have MATLAB, and if you downloaded the source code, then you want to use the,
Surabhi Simha: Launch Spindle GUI, which will open up, two tabs, and in that, you want to click the Launch Spindle Tutorial GUI.
Surabhi Simha: Oh yeah, so if you're doing this, you do need a math lab that's 2020A or later.
Surabhi Simha: It will not work if it's lower. Older than that, you do need signal processing toolbox, because there's a built, function.
Surabhi Simha: We actually don't need the full function for any of these, but because it's in the script, it will… it might complain if you don't have the signal processing toolbox installed. For those of you who don't know how to do this, you can go to add-ons, at the top ribbon of MATLAB, and I think you can say Manage Add-ons or, include add-ons, and that should… and then you can type in Signal Processing Toolbox.
Surabhi Simha: So if you can just, add that.
Surabhi Simha: It should be quick, so that'll help. These other things, you don't need it for now, but eventually it'll be nice for you to have them if you're going to run the, the script.
Surabhi Simha: And of course, if you don't have Math Lab, like I said before, you can just open the installer.
Surabhi Simha: I don't know if I mentioned this, I did realize that if you have Windows.
Surabhi Simha: If you have Windows, and you set your default to dark mode, then you will have
Surabhi Simha: and if you don't have MATLAB, that is, if you're using the installer, then you will have issues where the font color and the background color end up being the same, so you…
Surabhi Simha: If you run into that, please ask me, or maybe ask someone next to you.
Surabhi Simha: Yeah, if you do have Windows, and if your default is dark mode, I would actually suggest running it from MATLAB, just so that you can read the text. Yeah.
Surabhi Simha: That's some background. Any questions again?
Surabhi Simha: So, yeah, here's the,
Surabhi Simha: screenshot of what the GUI should look like if you launch the tutorial one.
Surabhi Simha: This… on the left side is what your first page will look like. There'll be 3 tabs. We'll be going through this guided walkthrough.
Surabhi Simha: And yeah, so we'll only… so like I said, if you use the source code, you'll see two,
Surabhi Simha: tabs. We will deal with the bottom one later. For now, we're going to be working through the interactive tutorial, which is the learning module.
Surabhi Simha: All right, so here's the same model from before. The whole script and the code consists of basically four, stages, but you go from length and activation as inputs to muscle spindle firing.
Surabhi Simha: So there's the extrafusal… oh, there. There's the extrafusal muscle tendon unit length.
Surabhi Simha: And Alpha Motor Drive, which is what you'll get, so these two.
Surabhi Simha: When you input these two, what the model does is it computes the fascicle length based on a force balance between the muscle fascicle and the tendon.
Surabhi Simha: And you'll notice at the bottom, there's a little name of the script. These are now made such that they can just be functions. So, if somebody is really into coding and modeling and has their own functions of modeling the muscle, the tendon, or spindle, or any of these segments.
Surabhi Simha: As long as you make the inputs and outputs match, you should be able to, like, swap out with your own script, and you're welcome to do that to see how things work.
Surabhi Simha: So that's the extrafusal part, so you input the extrafusal muscle tendon unit length in alpha, and get… takes a fascicle length, and like I said, the intrafusal fibers are in parallel to the extrafusal fascicle, which then means this fascicle length can get directly applied to those intrafusal muscle fibers.
Surabhi Simha: And but then you'll have to also give in gamma drive, which is the motor activation to the interfusal muscle fibers. So now you have the length of the intrafusal muscle fibers and their motor activations, which then means we can generate the cross-bridge mechanics, and… which eventually yields us the force.
Surabhi Simha: And then we take the force and the rate of change of force, which is, which is only for the bag. So we take the force goes up here, and the rate of change of force and force in the bag go down here. Each one of them gets, summed up, each one of them gets minimally weighted and summed up, and we end up with this receptor potential.
Surabhi Simha: And then finally, you can send the receptor potential through a spike generation or an integrated and fire function to give us actual spikes per second.
Surabhi Simha: Now, I will briefly talk about the spike generation, but this tutorial will not include that, and I'll explain why. You'll mostly, in this tutorial, you'll end up seeing receptive potential.
Surabhi Simha: But it should still give you the same intuition about how the muscle spindle firing itself occurs. And like I said, each of these is its own function.
Surabhi Simha: Each one calls the others sequentially, so if you have it, if you want to try different things, you can swap them out, or you can edit them.
Surabhi Simha: Right. So, you have inputs as alpha, MTU muscle tendon unit length, and alpha and gamma motor activations.
Surabhi Simha: And then the intermediate step, so, yeah, in the GUI, you might notice that there are little, tabs, little,
Surabhi Simha: identifiers that shows input, intermediate, and output. So that's just saying, whenever you're seeing, muscle… when you're seeing length and motor activations, they all have the input label, because that's what you, input to the model.
Surabhi Simha: And then all the intermediate streps, fascicle length, transverse distributions.
Surabhi Simha: forces yank, and then the output, like I said, is the receptor potential.
Surabhi Simha: The tutorial itself does not do the spike generation, so it does not… its output is not firing, but it's the receptor potential that's output.
Surabhi Simha: Now, there is also an option to input fascicle length, which I will talk about at the very end. The GUI does not have that option, but if you are comfortable coding yourself, there is an option to do that, and there's an example as well, which I will explain.
Surabhi Simha: Okay.
Surabhi Simha: So,
Surabhi Simha: just walking through… I took screenshots because I did realize things were slow, so I decided to go with screenshot as opposed to actually running the GUI live. But this is, what you should see if you step onto the first tab. The first row of the first step is length, so you have,
Surabhi Simha: What am I saying here? Yeah, so you have… the dotted line is the muscle tendon unit length, which is what you can input. So when you go to the breakout room, and when you go to the playground.
Surabhi Simha: You will be mostly commanding the dotted line.
Surabhi Simha: But then, you can… there's the fascicle lens which gets spotted for you.
Surabhi Simha: Like I said, there is an option to do that, just not in the GUI.
Surabhi Simha: And what you'll notice is that, classical length does not match the muscle tendon unit length, which, if you've done experiments, you know this already, and if you've done modeling too, you know this already.
Surabhi Simha: And that's because your fascicle has, alpha-motor activation, which can change the stiffness of the fascicle. So in this case, your muscle tendon unit length is just
Surabhi Simha: fixed, but because you activated your fascicle, your fascicle is shortening. And similarly, when you stretch the muscle tendon, together.
Surabhi Simha: Your fascicle also stretches, but how much it stretches is going to be related to the tendon stiffness that isn't serious with the fascicle, and also the activation of the fascicle. It's your alpha activity itself.
Surabhi Simha: And so… and because your intrafusal fibers are in parallel to the fascicle, they're not…
Surabhi Simha: battle to the muscle tendon, they experience those fascicle length changes, what… that's the length that gets applied to the intrafusal fiber.
Surabhi Simha: So, throughout, as we go through, I'm gonna,
Surabhi Simha: mention playground tasks, which is just, when you go to the breakout room, you'll open the playground tab.
Surabhi Simha: So, I'm going to compile a list of tasks. I'll also give you the whole compiled list before you actually go into the playground, but I'll pop them up as I go through each of these steps. So, one thing you can try in the playground is change this tendon stiffness.
Surabhi Simha: And also change the alpha motor activation to your extrafusal, and see how this relationship between your muscle tendon length and fascicle length changes.
Surabhi Simha: Now,
Surabhi Simha: just a note, this could break the model, which is fine, which I would like to know. I've tried to make sure it doesn't break it, but changing stiffness is one place where it has to do the force balance and depends on lots of
Surabhi Simha: complicated thing, so it could break it, which is fine. Please do, I would really appreciate if you can make a note of all the times it breaks and tell me.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, so that's the first… first step, row one.
Surabhi Simha: Your first step also has two other rows, which is activation and force.
Surabhi Simha: So, one of the activations I already talked about, that's the one in brown, this is your extrafusal activation, but also you have two intrafusal gamma-loaded activations. Now, these
Surabhi Simha: intrafusal fibers experience the same length, but you can give them their own independent activations. So that's what you're seeing here.
Surabhi Simha: In orange is your bag fibers activation, which is known as the gamma dynamic. This is just arbitrary selected activations, just to show that they can be different. You have a gamma static, which is your,
Surabhi Simha: Chain fiber activation in blue.
Surabhi Simha: And below in the bottom row, you see the force generated from each of these interfusal muscle fibers. So, in blue is the chain fiber force.
Surabhi Simha: And in orange is the bag fiber force. And you can see the bag one has a much sharper transient force. So, I guess your… what the…
Surabhi Simha: one detail you're missing is this increase in force coincides with the length change. So if you're actually looking at the GUI, you'll see that, there's… you start stretching roughly around here.
Surabhi Simha: And that's what's leading to this increase in force. This increase in force is because of you actually activating your interfusal muscle fibers.
Surabhi Simha: So, yeah, a couple of playground tasks from here is just to simply change your, gamma static and gamma dynamic. You can try to change them together, or change them separately, and see how that, changes your
Surabhi Simha: forces. And you'll also see, it's not just the magnitude of force that's different, but the whole shape of the force is also different between the two.
Surabhi Simha: So, also to note, what you're seeing down here is the total intrafusal fiber force, but,
Surabhi Simha: the interfusal hybrid force consists of an active component and a passive component. I'll talk about the active in the next one, but it's, as you can guess, it's from the cross bridges. There's just also a passive force in
Surabhi Simha: Under here, which is each muscle fib… each interfusal fiber, that's each bag and chain, has its own passive stiffness and its own slack length, which determines its passive force.
Surabhi Simha: So, another task is to change the stiffness. So keep the activation constant, but just change the passive stiffness of each of these fibers and see how that affects it. We… this is, again, these are all parameters, actually, the passive stiffness, especially.
Surabhi Simha: These are parameters that people have tried to estimate based on imaging and chemistry, but we don't have mechanical numbers for this. So if somebody wants to try and work on these things, that's also a way to improve the model if you're interested.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, so there is a… Row 2.1, so in the first page where you saw activation.
Surabhi Simha: This is something you do not have in the GUI, this is just something that's going on in the background that I'd just like to explain. So, model takes in
Surabhi Simha: activation, either as a percent of maximum, or a fraction of maximum, so it'll go between 0 and 1, or 0 and 100, based on how you define it. But, the cross-bridge model itself runs on PCA, which is concentration of calcium ions.
Surabhi Simha: So, I believe, like, a couple of, workshops ago, if you attended Hansel's workshop, you also saw the cross-bridge model there, taking in
Surabhi Simha: a calcium concentration as input. So…
Surabhi Simha: But you don't, as a user, you don't have… you don't deal with this unless you want to go into the scripts and vary it. So, I'm just showing you how the activation that you enter relates to the activation of the fiber itself in the model. So, first in the bottom row, your y-axis is
Surabhi Simha: your percent activation. So when you enter, say, 0.2 or 20% activation, like, this is the axis you're working on as a user inputting things, but it gets converted to this, YX axis, so X axis is PCA. So the sort of, like, pH when you measure acidity, it's just measuring,
Surabhi Simha: Instead of measuring hydrogen, you're measuring calcium concentration now, and what happens is, if you have a lower value, you end up with a higher activation, so 4.5, which is the maximum, gives you 100% activation, and 9 gives you a 0% activation.
Surabhi Simha: And in this figure down here, both your bag and chain are normalized, so you can get a sense of,
Surabhi Simha: when… assuming they're both normalized to their own maxes, this is what the curves look like. As you sweep across your activation, this is what you're doing to the calcium input that you're giving to each of the models.
Surabhi Simha: But here's the interesting thing. If you look on the top figure, now this is not normalized, so now your y-axis is just absolute force. You can see both the back and chain are doing very different things. So, when you pick 20% activation.
Surabhi Simha: You, the chain gets a calcium concentration of 6.5, whereas the bag gets something like, let's say 8.1.
Surabhi Simha: But then if you go up, a 6.5,
Surabhi Simha: 4. The force, the absolute force from a 6.5 concentration for chain is, already much higher, or it's the same as your bag being completely off, so your bag having 0% has a similar force as your chain having 20%.
Surabhi Simha: So, this may be a little confusing, but this is something… oh yeah, I didn't walk you through.
Surabhi Simha: So,
Surabhi Simha: If this is a little confusing, you can go to the playground and encourage, like, change the activation to bag and chain, change them by the same amount, change them by different amounts, and just look at how the forces change, and that might give you a little sense for how these curves translate to the activations that you input to the model.
Surabhi Simha: Up here, these are just, this is just showing you how, calcium concentration is measured, so PCA is minus log 10, CA2+, so that's why, because of the minus log 10, with lower values of calcium concentration, you get higher activations. And,
Surabhi Simha: So because of the crossbridge, how crossbridges work, more calcium means that more cross bridges can bind, and more active force, which is what we'll see in the slide.
Surabhi Simha: So this is step two in your GUI. You can click next on that tab, and you should be taken to this page, where the right-hand side shows you the screenshot I'm showing here.
Surabhi Simha: This is exactly, like, how cross-bridge muscle models work, which you, learned about the last two workshops, I think. So,
Surabhi Simha: it's the same thing, except you just now have two cross-bridge models, instead of one extra fusil one. So in the top row is the length that we saw. There's the muscle tendon length, muscle fascicle length that comes out of it, and then in the bottom, you see how the cross bridges are changing. So, the model is… consists of two
Surabhi Simha: is made up of cross bridges, right? So when you stretch a cross bridge, the crossbridge gets pulled to the right.
Surabhi Simha: which means, because each cross bridge is modeled essentially as a spring, your whole distribution, which is down here during early stretch, so you start… well, I guess it's sort of mid-stretch, but you stretch the muscle and muscle fascicle, which means you stretch all the cross bridges.
Surabhi Simha: And they go from being basically centered mostly around zero to getting pulled to the right. Now, you have two distributions, because you have bag and chain. The red is the bag cross bridges, and blue is the chain cross bridges.
Surabhi Simha: But they both experience the same length change, so they both get stretched to the right, which then gives you a force,
Surabhi Simha: Assuming there's springs, and then you add some of the force from each cross bridge.
Surabhi Simha: And then, when you relax, that's… this, post-stretch is all the way from here, when the cross bridges have reached straight state again, and now you see all the… in both for the bag and chain, the cross bridges are back over the center.
Surabhi Simha: So, playground tasks. In the playground, you have a little, like, a little bar that you can slide across. So you'll only see one crossroads distribution, but you can slide the bar to see what the distributions are doing across time for one simulation. So, I would encourage you to slide the bar.
Surabhi Simha: then change the attachment and detachment rates, because that'll determine how those distributions are in steady state, and also how they respond to a stretch. So change the attachment and detachment rates with both bag and chain, and then again, slide the… slide it and see how the cross bridges change.
Surabhi Simha: distribution changes.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, so those are all forces.
Surabhi Simha: But we actually want to get to muscle spindle firing, so how this works is
Surabhi Simha: We have force in the step.
Surabhi Simha: And our model basically takes the force and also computes the rate of change of force that's defined as yank, or termed as yank.
Surabhi Simha: And it only takes that for this bag fiber, so this orange line, it takes the rate of change of this orange line, and that is the yank that's plotted in this third row now. And you can see, when there is… at the beginning of the stretch, there's a shard price in bag force, which means there's a shard price in yank.
Surabhi Simha: And then all of these, gets… they each get their own weighting, and they get added up.
Surabhi Simha: to get this receptor potential. So now your blue line here is just a weighted value of this blue line up here, whereas your orange R, which is your orange potential, is a weighted sum of this orange line, and also this purple line.
Surabhi Simha: But the… because you can see the yank goes negative, we don't use that. We,
Surabhi Simha: So that's the half-wave rectification, which mostly applies to the yank, so we get rid of the negative, and then we sum them up. That is a low-pass filter, but pretty much for anything you simulate, it
Surabhi Simha: doesn't apply, because simulations are already very clean. This is in place mostly if you want to run empirical data, which can be quite noisy.
Surabhi Simha: Yeah, so the playground task for this is so you have knobs that, deal with the gain, that's the weighting on the bag and chain, and also the yank, and you can see how changing those weightings will change this, total receptor potential.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, I'm gonna go quickly through this one. This is… the model can give you spikes, that is a
Surabhi Simha: You get receptor potential, which is a continuous signal, it's the voltage across the, encoding, like, the spice-initiating region, but typically, when you measure from a
Surabhi Simha: know, when you measure from a money afferent, what you measure are action potential. So you'll… if you see an empirical recording, you'll see data that is spikes per second.
Surabhi Simha: So to convert this, the… what our model does is it runs it through a very basic integrated fire function that just does a cumulative integral of the voltage, and then generates a spike for every X time steps, and then plots that as spikes per second.
Surabhi Simha: But, purely because of how the model is implemented, because this is a discrete model, and it… I chose,
Surabhi Simha: time step of 1 millisecond, that is, the model runs at 1000Hz. It means that, it just has a limit of 250 spikes per second, but it's purely because of how things are implemented.
Surabhi Simha: Now, for anything, that is… oh, yeah, so you can… if you run it at a much higher frequency, you can push up this threshold, but also it means your models is going to take forever, and it's a trade-off. But
Surabhi Simha: under the ceiling of those 250Hz, that's what you're showing. In the first example, I showed you a condition where it's just…
Surabhi Simha: hitting the ceiling, so your firing is flat and there's no information there. But then, in the second example, here's the same ceiling.
Surabhi Simha: And now in the top row, this is the receptive potential, and in the bottom row is the firing that comes from the receptor potential. So, if you're under the 250Hz,
Surabhi Simha: ceiling, your receptor… your firing rate looks pretty similar to the receptor potential. So for this, tutorial, I basically
Surabhi Simha: remove the firing, so you… all the results you see will be receptor potential, but it should still give you the same intuition for what the firing rate's doing. Simply because I want to let you play around with much more parameters, which, is possible if it doesn't threshold.
Surabhi Simha: Yeah, so,
Surabhi Simha: But if you do want to go into the MATLAB script yourself, you can, there is the… there's an example… there is a folder called Examples, which has, spikes from a separate potential MATLAB script.
Surabhi Simha: that runs those integrate and fire function. So you can do that. Or if you're much more ambitious, there's a whole paper where they really… they modeled how the ion channels work. So the way you go from, receptor potential to spikes is, like, your voltage passes through ion channels, and that's how our, like, our,
Surabhi Simha: we get the spikes. So you can look at those papers, and if you are so inclined and would like to develop a module, you can develop, and I'm happy to integrate it with this tutorial, too.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, so that was the run-through. Took a little bit longer than I thought. So we can go into the breakout rooms now, which, I think Victoria can help me, that would be great.
Surabhi Simha: Yeah, so basically go through the playground. Oh, so here, here's the… all the tasks.
Surabhi Simha: If you can, maybe you can take a screenshot of these,
Surabhi Simha: things to try in the playground, and you can try them when you're there. By no means you're restricted to this. Feel free to try
Surabhi Simha: whatever you want. Talk to each other so if you can help each other when the other person gets stuck, especially if you're working between Mac and Windows and the app versus the direct Math Lab, it'd be great if you can help each other out. And, yeah, please discuss and come back with questions.
Surabhi Simha: Oh, I have this up again here, just in case somebody missed this.
Victoria Wood: Alright, great. I will post that list of the playground, tasks as well in the Slack, so you can see that if you didn't get a chance to get a screenshot. And then I have breakout rooms here. Each of the watch parties has their own breakout room. If you are on the Zoom
Victoria Wood: like, on your own, but you're in the same physical space as a watch party, just stay in this main room and I'll reassign you.
Victoria Wood: Oh, Monica, you didn't get assigned, do you want to join one, or…
Monica Daley (she, her): Why didn't I get assigned?
Victoria Wood: I didn't do the… the hosts don't automatically get assigned to your co-host.
Monica Daley (she, her): Oh, I see. Okay. Well, I don't know who to join,
Victoria Wood: We can.
Monica Daley (she, her): I'll go to room 3, maybe?
Victoria Wood: Yeah, you should do room.
Lena Ting (she/her): Victoria invited me to Room 1.
Victoria Wood: Hey, Rachel.
Victoria Wood: Were you able to join a breakout room? I don't know if you have.
Victoria Wood: If you're frozen or something.
Victoria Wood: Hey!
Surabhi Simha: Hi.
Victoria Wood: How's it going in there?
Surabhi Simha: That's good, yeah, so I started talking to them and explaining things to them, and then realized maybe I should, like, hop around, yeah.
Victoria Wood: Cool. Okay, let me make sure… you should be able to hop between rooms. I think I have that setting, just the default.
Victoria Wood: But I don't think…
Surabhi Simha: occurrence? Oh, yeah.
Victoria Wood: Yes, yeah, so you should just be able to join whichever one you want.
Surabhi Simha: Oh, was I in… 2 just now?
Victoria Wood: Or just in two, yeah.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, great. Thanks. See you next.
Victoria Wood: I think you're muted.
Surabhi Simha: Oh, yeah, I just said I'll just keep hopping. I came out of one. Yeah, it's fun to hear all the different issues people have.
Victoria Wood: That's, like, always the case if you share code.
Surabhi Simha: Yeah, but it's all good feedback, so it's fine. Good. Okay. Gonna find room 3. So I see a bunch of rooms with only one person, is that intentional?
Victoria Wood: Yes, so those are the watch parties, so those are the people that are, yeah, just, like, in a conference room together.
Surabhi Simha: Okay.
Surabhi Simha: Cool, I will hop to the next one.
Surabhi Simha: Anything I can help with?
Victoria Wood: I think… what's been fine here so far. I think mine's watched pretty just…
Victoria Wood: They might need to rejoin, but no, we're good.
Surabhi Simha: I'm gonna…
Victoria Wood: She actually broadcasts to all rooms. There's about 10 minutes left.
Victoria Wood: So we'll end at 1.15, you said, right?
Surabhi Simha: Yeah, so I can walk through a little bit more.
Surabhi Simha: Yep.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, well…
Victoria Wood: Alright, everybody should be back from their breakout rooms now.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, can you see my screen again now?
Surabhi Simha: Awesome. So, I was going to do questions now, but I want to quickly run through the other tab, and then do questions together at the end, if that's okay.
Surabhi Simha: Anybody who really has a question they want to ask now can go quickly.
Surabhi Simha: Alright, so I'm gonna run through… oh, this is sick.
Surabhi Simha: Oh, gosh.
Victoria Wood: Okay, sorry.
Surabhi Simha: Good.
Surabhi Simha: All right, so this is the second part of the model, which, if you only download the installer or the app, you do not have this, because this does require some MacLab skills and a little bit of coding, so…
Surabhi Simha: If you downloaded the source code and you, ran that, you would have probably… when you ran the GUI, you probably got two things. One was the analysis toolkit, so that's what we'll go through now.
Surabhi Simha: The reason I want to do this is, because of the Your Data tab. So if you run the analysis, you'll get this too, there's gamma optimization in your data.
Surabhi Simha: The gamma optimization is a little more… also a tutorial, basically, but for optimization, but your data is where you can take your own data, and then you can run it through things. So there are two ways you can run your data through the model.
Surabhi Simha: One is, the forward model, so that's the first, the green button here.
Surabhi Simha: For this, what you'll need is you'll need to input the MTU length, that is your muscle tendon unit length.
Surabhi Simha: So, this is maybe what's useful for many of you, because, most of you do collect these data, so you can… if you don't directly have the muscle tendon length, you might have, giant angles, and you can go from giant angles to muscle tendon length, using your moment turns.
Surabhi Simha: But some of you might also directly measure fascicle length through ultrasound, if it's, like, whole body movement, or maybe you do sono micrometry crystals if you're doing animal work. So if you have fascicle length directly, you can choose which one you input.
Surabhi Simha: So in this GUI, there are two options. There is a load built-in example, which you can… this is a simulated example, so it runs cleanly, the model created the example. So you can try a load built-in, and then run forward. You can try that if you want as you're listening to me.
Surabhi Simha: It should give you a result.
Surabhi Simha: Alternately, you can load a MAT file, and the MAT file will require… you can click load matte file and upload a MAT file, but it just needs to have, these inputs, and I'll also show a slide of how to format the input. But the MAT file requires your muscle tendon length or fascicle length.
Surabhi Simha: And then it requires activation. So one activation is, alpha motor drive, so you can normalize this to… you can choose how you want, for your research, but you'll have… it'll have to be between 0 and 1, or 0 and 100, depending on if…
Surabhi Simha: If you're doing a fraction of the maximum, it'll be 0 and 1. If it's a percentage, it's 0 and 100. And if you don't tell it which one it is, and if you just… if it just detects it's more than 1.5, it automatically assumes it's a percent, because you can't have 1.5 of max.
Surabhi Simha: So this will be your alpha recording, this is the EMG signals that you measure from your muscle, but because it's a forward run, which you tried in the playground, it also needs motor activations to interfusal muscles. Now, this is something almost no one has. I don't think anyone actually has this at all, because you have to measure the gamma motor activity.
Surabhi Simha: So, a couple of options for if you're interested, and say you measure your,
Surabhi Simha: you measured your muscle activations and muscle lengths, and you want to know what could be the spindle firing, you could just sweep different, gamma activations. You just give it, have it run through a forum loop or something, and then have it, just give it different kinds of gamma activations, and that'll give you a spread of the different, muscle spindle
Surabhi Simha: Firing that's possible for this activity that you're measuring from this person or animal.
Surabhi Simha: Or, if you have a specific prediction of what you expect to be happening, you can also just give it that gamma motor activity and see the spindle firing, and see if that results in behavior. Because remember, the spindle firing feeds back to alpha motor activity, so maybe you measure reflexes, and you want to see how this reflex changes, so you can have a prediction of gamma activity and see if your reflux matches that.
Surabhi Simha: output. This is with the GUI, so those are restricted, but you can just go in and
Surabhi Simha: write your scripts yourselves. So, these are the different three functions you will need. That's the setup tutorial part, so you just need parts to all the functions, and you'll need to load user data. So this function is what this button calls.
Surabhi Simha: And then you need the run forward, from data, and this function is what this green button calls, so each button is a function.
Surabhi Simha: And, if you go into the examples folder, there is an example script, run my own data, which… it's an example script that calls all these functions properly, so it's a starting point, and you can
Surabhi Simha: use that to know how to structure your data and how to input data. So if you're used to, coding with MATLAB, I'd say go to run my own data.m and see how it works, and then see how you can edit it with your own data from there.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, so the second thing you can do to run your own data is maybe you want to predict the gamma drive. So, like I said, we do not know what gamma motor drive is. So now I'm, dealing with the second half of this,
Surabhi Simha: Second half of this,
Surabhi Simha: GUI, which is not run forward, but it's an optimization.
Surabhi Simha: But because it's an optimization, you do not need to give it gamma motor drive, but you do need to give it spindle firing. So this means that you are one of those people, somebody who's measuring from muscle spindles, from humans or other animals.
Surabhi Simha: So the length and alpha motor activation look the same, they're structured exactly the same, except in sort of
Surabhi Simha: giving gamma motor activations, you give it muscle spindle in your MAT file.
Surabhi Simha: Or, again, you can skip the GUI, so instead of loading that mat file, you just go run it through the same script. The same run example script has these. The only difference is you're now calling run optFromData instead of run forward, so that now runs the optimization.
Surabhi Simha: The way the optimization works is it's just a cycle, so the optimization script, it guesses its certain motor activations, and it runs a forward simulation to generate the muscle spindle,
Surabhi Simha: firing, the corrected muscle spindle output, and then it compares it with the muscle spindle firing that you gave it to generate a cost. And then it keeps doing this cycle until it can minimize the cost, and until it thinks that there is no more lower cost possible.
Surabhi Simha: The GUI is, limited in how the different ways you can parameterize your gamma drive, but this is something I'll hopefully improve in the next versions of the model.
Surabhi Simha: Right now, it takes gamma dynamic to be something that bursts on and off, and all you get… and it's hard-coded when it, bursts on and off, and
Surabhi Simha: the optimization just sets the magnitude. This is… I already have a version that can take anything, I just haven't updated the model. So if you're interested, please ask me, and I will give you a version that just takes any arbitrary gamma dynamic.
Surabhi Simha: And same for gamma static, it parameterizes it as a spline, so you can play around here. So, this one… so down here, you have… have some preset ways to parametrize your gamma static.
Surabhi Simha: You can choose different ones and see what works. If you're dealing with a periodic movement, like something like locomotion, it enforces periodicity just to help the optimizer find it. It's just, if you know it's going to be periodic, it helps.
Surabhi Simha: But you don't have to, you can make it be not periodic, you can just make it be flat. The options just help you converge better, because
Surabhi Simha: It helps to optimize those to converge if you can constrain what all they're searching.
Surabhi Simha: So those of you who are used to optimizations, there's also a couple of different ways you can optimize. Mmcon is the default, which is a gradient-based solver, but there's also a non-gradient-based solver, which I have as patent search, because this can be a pretty tricky optimization.
Surabhi Simha: And, finally, the default optimization is it take… it
Surabhi Simha: It takes the receptive potential from the model and fits it to the firing, which, most cases works, but you can change it to be actual firing rate, because there is a spike in the integrate and fire function, so you can change and ask the model to fit its firing to actual firing, and that is also… that also works.
Surabhi Simha: And then this is, like I said, you can take a screenshot, or maybe, I guess this is all recorded, but this is, if you want to input your own data, these are the various, variables you'll have to make sure is in your mat file.
Surabhi Simha: You always want a time, and you always want, length, which is your muscle tendon or fascicle length. Make sure they're the same… the same length. I'm saying lens twice, but, they should have the same number of elements, both of them.
Surabhi Simha: And then you can give alpha activation, or it defaults to zero, and then you want to give it gamma activation if you're doing a forward run, like I said, but if you're doing an optimization, you don't.
Surabhi Simha: And if you're doing an optimization, you want to give it a 1A afferent firing, or if you're doing forward run, you don't need to give it. And then tendon stiffness is something you can also change, but it defaults to 5,000.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, so that's… I want to give some time questions. I have, this just image showing how to use the Gamma Optimization tab, which is just a tutorial for you to play around with the sandbox optimization.
Surabhi Simha: But because I want, to give you time for questions, I'll just, give you the take-homes and let you ask me questions, so…
Surabhi Simha: Hopefully, you all have an idea of what the muscle spindle is, and that we use biophysical modeling because, to capture all the properties of the spindle, and hopefully you now have a model that you can use to, run your own data on.
Surabhi Simha: Okay, thank you. Oh, yeah, here.
Surabhi Simha: I'll take questions.
Surabhi Simha: Yes.
Monica Daley (she, her): That was really cool, and thank you so much for sharing this model. It's really useful, for illustrating all of these
Monica Daley (she, her): interactions. I'm wondering, because this seems like there's a lot of parameters that have to go into this model, and so I was wondering how you approach
Monica Daley (she, her): Like, setting the default parameters for this thing.
Surabhi Simha: Yeah, that's a great question.
Surabhi Simha: we don't know most of the parameters, I would say. Like, we don't know, the ground truth. We don't have… they haven't been measured, because,
Surabhi Simha: Those of you who work with extra refusal pivers, you already know at the cross-bridge level, you already don't really… even for the extra refusal, it's pretty hard to know the attachment and detachment rates and things like that.
Surabhi Simha: The intrafusal fibers are even smaller, so nobody's actually done mechanical testing to try and get these parameters. What they have done, though, which lots of people have done, I read these papers and it's…
Surabhi Simha: Seems like really hard work. What they do is, like, the initial, slides that I showed, so maybe here?
Surabhi Simha: What they've done is just look under a microscope, stain them in different ways, and also they've done a lot of,
Surabhi Simha: what chemistry molecular characterizations. So, they know what types of my… what type of myosin types are in these fibers, and they also have a sense of stiffness, where
Surabhi Simha: They have… so, in fact, this one, this was done a while ago, in 1979, but they actually had… they dissected a full spindle, put it on a…
Surabhi Simha: under a microscope, and they pulled at it. But I think back then, they didn't have
Surabhi Simha: they didn't have strain gauges attached to it, so they didn't actually measure the forces, but, somebody who knows these techniques more can maybe tell me, it seems like they did all the work to get it in a setup where you could actually measure the mechanical properties if you had,
Surabhi Simha: chain gauges or something attached, but they did not. They only… all they had was a microscope. So, yeah, short answer is, it's mostly from, these, optical, measurements and, also, chemistry of.
Surabhi Simha: what types of proteins are involved in making these, that people have made guesses of what the properties might be, and that's how we input the properties. And more directly in this model itself, what we did was we fit the output.
Surabhi Simha: So we have, we can measure, primary 1A affine firing from rats and cats and a bunch of animals, where, the animals… and it's often they're anesthetized because it's very invasive, but we can fit that… so it's limited, but we can fit that firing
Surabhi Simha: to our model, and we can basically say.
Surabhi Simha: let's find the parameters that… of these models that gives us the firing rate. So there's a lot of layers that it's absorbing. Those numbers are absorbing all of these changes, for sure. But that's how we do it in this model.
Surabhi Simha: Does that explain?
Monica Daley (she, her): Yep.
Surabhi Simha: Any other questions?
Surabhi Simha: Let's… Stop sharing, yeah.
Victoria Wood: All right, I guess, if no other questions, I think that's all we have for today. Don't forget to fill out the capstone RSVP survey if you're coming in person, and then you can continue to post questions in the Slack if you can think of anything afterwards.
Victoria Wood: And we'll try to get answers to you.
Surabhi Simha: Thank you.
Monica Daley (she, her): Thank you. That was fun.
Surabhi Simha: Glide.
Chastain, Maddy: Thank you.
Victoria Wood: That's great, thanks so much!